After we have seen the hash table data structure, how it works and how it stores data, let's implement
the hash table and see, first of all, we will start by include SD, i o and include that SD.
Is the deal the edge?
We start by creating the structure called set it took into it have in the very variables, the key and
the date we have set that the key and the data are linked together.
We create an array capacity and size integers.
Know we will create a function called hash function.
It took into the parameter in key and returns a and end this end.
Well, this is the returning type of this function.
How what, what will return?
It will return the key modulo capacity.
OK.
This is the hash function.
This is the algorithm that we have created in this function.
OK, it's very simple.
We are just getting that key that is best in the perimeter, and we made that modular operation and
therefore that capacity now would create another function called Check Prime.
It is.
It is containing an integer.
As a part of me, they're called RN and.
We start by creating and I it's returning type is in the show, so we need to return an integer if an
equal equal to one or an equal equal to zero, then return zero.
OK.
We are checking if it is appropriate.
So we pass an integer here and we check if there's a problem.
Now if we need to make.
A loop that starts by from equal to do and I less than and over to which start dividing this number
in order to find its if it is a prime or not, if and module you are equal equal to zero, then returns
zero.
So it is visible.
So it is not an upright.
Therefore, if this this loop is not returning anything, and if this condition is not returning anything,
then return one.
So it is a prior number.
We need to create another function called Get Prime Passing and Model two and Model two, equal equal
to two equals equal to zero then and plus plus so increase and by one white check prime.
This is that the.
The function that we have created before.
And we check the prime.
If it is, while it does not equal a prime then and equal and that old and plus two and then return
and.
We create another function called initialize array initialized in each array.
Capacity equal to get prime capacity.
And this is the function that we have created before and to create an array equal, the structure set
that we also we have created the structure set.
We are creating an object from it, but in sea there is no object.
Remember, like thinking about it as an object.
So we are reserving them melodic memory allocation, creating a structure like the set up and we make
a loop for it into equal to zero I less than capacity.
I + + then initialized the array array.
At index, I took key equal to zero and array and equal data equal to zero, then make this array equal.
All the numbers inside equal, all the values are equal to zero.
Create another method called Insert Insert will give the key and and data as parking meters and we start
and index, we create a number or sorry if valuable of type and called index hash function.
We make hashing for that key.
So we have created a hash function.
We have we have created a hash value since the hash function that we have created before.
It will return a key modular capacity.
So we are returning an integer.
OK.
So.
This will return and index.
After hashing key.
If array appendix, the data equal equal to zero, then it is an empty, so stored that information.
Bypassing that array at index index, the key equal to equal to key and array at index index, the data
equal to data, we are inserting the data and the key and increased size by one, therefore print f
key it has been inserted successfully.
OK.
Otherwise else, if at index index, that key equal, equal to key, there exist another data then as
the index index does data equal to data.
So this is empty slot, this is occupied the slot and this will make a collision occurred when we have
that data equal to date.
Now the remove element, this is the method that we will make in order to remove the elements from that
hash table.
We will start by making the hashing for that and the key that that is best and we start it inside the
variable called index.
We start checking by.
If early at index index, the data are equal equal to zero, then the key does not exist.
OK.
Else are they at index index 30 equal to zero?
Make it as zero.
And make that data and the key equal to zero.
And decrease the size by one.
Therefore, the key has been removed.
We will continue by making another display function.
Start from I, I equal to zero I less than capacity if array index I, the data are equal, equal to
zero, then print as vague this so print all the elements.
Otherwise we put the key and the value date, OK?
No, another that another method of type, returning type and size of hash table it for the target would
return their size.
OK.
It's very simple.
Now let's go to the main function and see the algorithm.
We will create and measures the choice that key data and and and see equal to zero.
And we call the function in shade the say that we have created here.
We start by making a do while loop, so this is that do.
And this is the wide loop.
This would be executed that the first day.
Then we check the condition.
If it is true, then we are going to.
Go back and execute that, do what?
Print of this is printing, just printing.
Switch there is a switch if we have a choice, he.
If the choice variable here is one.
We get the key from the user, we get the data from the user.
We call the method insert that we have created here and we have inserted it successfully.
If it is not, we have seen this in many cases.
Discussed that if there's equal equal to zero, then we can insert it into correctly, and if array
at index index the equal equal to the key, then insert it.
Otherwise, it will make and collision occurred and does not insert anything.
Case number two Enter the key two to delete.
We can make deleting, so scan f we can delete the function.
So we called that remove element function so we can delete the key and the vector.
The third case is an equal to size of hash table, so we are getting the hash table size and the printing
at the fourth case as this play.
Display, we are just displaying the hash table and default print at invalid input, so the user will
build enter that number of their choice.
If it one, then it will execute the insertion.
If it is, do, it will remove that element.
Three, it will return the size and if it's four, it will display that.
The tape was sequel equal to what I want from you to write this code inside your C compiler and the
check and play with the codes and order to understand.